The Cowboy and the Frenchman is a comedy, western film directed by David Lynch.
A grizzled, hard-of-hearing cowboy, Slim, and his two friends, Dusty
and Pete, capture a mysterious, well-dressed Frenchman.
Slim, played by Harry Dean Stanton.
Pierre the Frenchman, played by Frederic Golchan.
Dusty, played by Tracey Walter.
Pete, played by Jack Nance.
Broken Feather, played by Michael Horse.
Howdy, played by Rick Guillory.
The Short Films of David Lynch (2002) is a DVD collection of the early student
and commissioned film work of American filmmaker David Lynch.
As such, the collection does not include Lynch's later short
works, which are listed in the filmography.
The DVD contains introductions by Lynch to each film.
The film explores themes of surreal, surrealism, short film.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.